Halloween's not over yet so I'm still
smiling welcome back to another episode
of hermitcraft I'm sorry I can't talk to
the camera like this it doesn't look
right I don't look right it looks so
wrong so continuing our format of
working on the base a little bit at the
start of every episode because I
definitely don't want to abandon this
project it's definitely not done and
indeed I want to continue the mission of
symmetry no not false symmetry true
symmetry I need to make this side here
the same as the one over there and for
that to happen I need to start digging
again digging a lot that actually
includes quite a lot of gravel placing
to get rid of water but actually it also
includes quite a lot of TNT now I don't
know if you remember but when I dug out
this hole I didn't actually dig most of
it it was actually made mostly by TNT
and then tidied up afterwards it was
only that section at the back that was
actually mined out so I've got myself
some TNT as I always do gotta keep gotta
keep TNT spare just for this sort of
thing and we're gonna make our way down
to bedrock at least I think it's Bedrock
now digging straight down is never a
good idea make your way all the way back
up now this is still a very long process
don't get me wrong but it's still a lot
faster than mining it all by hand
well it's not going to be that fast then
is it what's going on
help help okay alternating TNT didn't
work here we go oh whoa now I'm gonna
need an awful lot of TNT to do this
entire area I still stand by it that it
is the quickest way of mining okay so
I've used up what I had and that was
three and a half stacks of TNT and I've
only covered a very very small portion
of this area so let's do what we always
love to do ignite the TNT and see what
happens
well I mean I don't know why I didn't
expect anything other than a giant
explosion but check it out
exactly what we wanted oh it's a pit of
silverfish I wasn't really expecting
that right so no diamonds but we do know
that we need a lot more TNT if we're
gonna get this whole thing looking a bit
more like this so believe it or not we
actually need to travel to the upside
down which I haven't been to in a long
long time yeah I don't miss traveling
down this tunnel very much I must admit
now the reason that I actually came to
the upside down is because the only
desert biome that I know of is actually
just on the other side of this portal
the desert that we allocated at the
beginning of the season is now
completely empty I mean just bear that
in mind for a second I mean just just
imagine for a second every single block
of this sand is gone there just how much
sand do we get through it's it's
industrial sized Minecraft but you know
what I've done I've done quite a stupid
that I've done quite stupid I didn't
bring any shulker boxes with me so this
isn't going to be great but I'll tell
you what we're gonna do we're gonna put
some chests down and we are gonna do a
very quick grind lapse as we fill all of
these up with sand until our shovel is
nearly broken without further Ado let's
let's mine some sand
[Music]
so as you saw I have made up some TNT
and guess what each one of these is
about a stack so I can't believe this
but this is um not actually the most
efficient way because when you factor in
all the item collecting for each of
these TNT it's actually going to take a
long time so let's just uh let's ignite
these and hope for the best because they
are placed in a way that should
what
I blew up my own base
and I let out the goons
they must have been sitting in there for
a long time I've I've ruined my storage
as well but there's no denying that it's
been a fairly successful explosion but
it might be safer just to mine it out
normally when I do this it shows some
diamonds but absolutely no diamonds
today so on the whole
I don't know
puns
on the whole it is not a very big hole
uh but I have quite a lot more Mining
and Excavating and explosions to do so
this will be again a project that takes
me roughly a million episodes but let's
go over to the shopping district now
where there's actually while there's
still time some Halloween games I really
should do the Halloween games while it's
still technically before Halloween whoa
big surprise massive pyramid awesome I
actually helped Ren with the shape of
that a while ago so I'm so glad to see
that it's uh actually made it in game so
in regards to the mycelium resistance I
have another little explanation mind
games to do but before I get to that we
need to go and do this thing which is
the Halloween trick or treat house the
trick-or-treat House costumes required
well I have a costume on there we go
it's my face it's a that's actually
b-dubs's face I've got his face on it's
recommended to store all items before
trick-or-treating okay that's fair so
what do I actually need to do here trick
or treat press ceiling button inside I
don't have to pay for anything right
there was no payment required oh
I've been treated
oh my goodness
that's one two three four five six seven
eight nine that's three with us three
Withers I I'm flabbergasted that is an
actual treat are you sure I don't have
to pay for this
is there some sort of is this a trick I
mean don't don't get me wrong that's
great but is this a genuine trick
because there's no payment there's
nothing required as far as I can tell
can I get treated again please
okay
I've been tricked you have two minutes
to live oh my goodness okay all right so
I've been I've been tricked now uh see
the item in the left Barrel
the left Barrel
red wool
use the uh use the items in the right
Barrel to make the same item put your
new item in the center Barrel exit
through the back uh you hear this okay
how do I
how do I do this
how do I make a red wool
using
this there's enough to make an iron
golem right not like that uh-oh okay so
I have an iron golem I'm pretty sure I
wasn't oh wait am I meant to kill him
with lava what does he drop
I think I can do this
but I have only two minutes come on I
can't burn the items come on
faster burn faster okay uh
is it full
no no no no no no no no no no
I was so it was so close
okay
oh no
uh no I figured it out too late okay can
we do that again can I get another guy
oh it's so close if I hadn't spent such
a stupid amount of time reading the book
reading you see reading got me killed I
actually know how to get out of here
okay we gotta try this again now that I
know what to do hopefully it gives me
the same the same trick I think all
right all right all right we can do this
unless I get a treat a treat I got
treated oh my goodness it's the shovel
Shuffle heck yeah check it out it's the
shovel Shuffle
okay right we need to get tricked again
here we go
oh I don't think I meant to use this
again
right right right right let's do this
properly oh pumpkin pie
oh man this is a I don't even know how
to make pumpkin pie
I genuinely don't even know how to make
pumpkin pie
well this isn't good I I've no I I I'm
stumped
what would a pumpkin pie be made out of
exactly I give up
I give up to be honest I was lost on
pumpkin pie for that one genuinely like
it was it was over from the word pumpkin
pie I haven't I don't think I've ever
crafted pumpkin pie okay one more time
one more trick I feel like this is such
a good crafting challenge I don't know
I've if you guys know how the pumpkin
pie one was done I'm mind blown I've
managed to get the wool one eventually
but like I just ran out of time oh
another treat
oh my goodness that's see that's
thanks I didn't even notice there was a
treat thing there I was too busy looking
at the Box all right here we go it seems
to be treat trick treat trick treat
trick all right let's go
we don't need to check this it seems to
be the same piston how do we make a
piston we use the stuff in here how do
we use the stuff in here
uh how do I get the redstone ore okay
right I think this is fairly simple
if I'm
correct we're gonna have to make
a wooden pickaxe to turn this into
cobblestone
we're gonna run out of time
and then oh no because I need that for
the the Piston maybe this
straight away for this maybe oh maybe
I've messed up
oh I've messed up have I messed up
because it's one Redstone it's one red
stone piston there we go there we go
there we go I did it what happened
I made the Piston I made it
why is it still going off help
what's supposed to happen help
what door what door this door
this door
what door there was no door I actually
managed it this time look apparent Tango
says that the lava should have gone down
but it didn't
I'm gonna I feel like I'm hogging this
but I feel like I really need to to win
this oh Tiger's here all right furnace I
have to make a furnace using
these blocks
with no word I need to make a furnace
how do I oh okay what can I make out of
this TNT TNT TNT I can make a TNT
yes and then I can make
I can make come on
come on
TNT and then I can turn
come on I need this for a flint and
steel this is luck based
this is totally luck based
oh my I figured it out I know exactly
how to do there we go right we can make
one of these we then we then go and make
one of these
oh we're probably gonna die from the
explosion here
then we got
boom furnace right now we put just one
in
and the lava comes down
oh
oh no oh wait does it only open for a
second
for real
it opens it opens for like half a second
this is insane it opens for half a
second okay right I'm gonna stop being
selfish because there's gonna be some
other Hermits that desperately want to
play this even though I really really
want to continue so badly I just I want
to win but I feel like I've definitely
had my turn now if if Tango an Impulse
say I can go again then I will but I
feel like I feel I feel like I've had
enough so what was the explanation for
the mycelium resistance well oh it's
pretty pretty funny actually so I need
to play a clip again from last week of
me and impulse doing some mind game
scheming here we go
uh we have not an issue because I've
already solved the issue but we have an
opportunity so Ren and I used this here
secret bubble elevator to spread the
sheep and in turn spread the mycelium
but a lot of the the viewers we 100 IQ
them Bamboozled I said 200 IQ Bamboozled
them and they were like oh I can't
believe you you've revealed the bass
again but we haven't I sealed up the
tunnel oh smart as soon as as soon as we
were done the tunnel is sealed this is
just an empty bubble elevator and
there's no base down there the base is
miles away oh so they cannot just
backtrack through this to find our
actual headquarters absolutely not but
good job it's good thinking man I
wouldn't have thought of that they think
they can they don't know that I've
sealed it up and the viewers have
probably told them that Ren and I in
quotations messed up so what I'm
thinking is we build a tunnel that
backtracks to your fake imposter base we
update the base to make it look legit
again yep and then lead them to a trap
now they I I don't know if you know but
there's some diamonds missing from the
diamond Throne we use the buyback
program to steal all their Diamonds oh
good good so you guys put that mycelium
I've been collecting to good use exactly
nice we we have put the diamonds in our
vault so if we make a fake fault we can
assume that they will try and steal the
diamonds
wow yes we're like three moves ahead of
them three yeah dude we are we are three
moves ahead right so here's the here's
what I'm suggesting I'll make the tunnel
because it's not going to be fun to
Tunnel all that distance I'll tell you
yes very far make it look legit and then
if you take care of the Vault trap and
updating the the decoy base to what it
looks like now we got ourselves a triple
bamboozle
perfect I love this plan no more
knockoff decoy headquarters it's going
to be legit it'd be legit
how many times are they gonna fall for
the same decoy oh my gosh yeah I'm gonna
make it look different they won't even
know they'll probably think it's like
yeah they're gonna think it's the real
headquarters I got this
so I went ahead and I did that I made
the tunnel it goes all the way down here
and leads
in a very long way
all the way I mean and it's very long a
very very convincing fake
Pace we've now led the hip to this fake
base twice purely because we were able
to update this I mean you can't tell
looking at this this looks like the real
thing did they trample my crops
I think they trampled my crops so this
is the fake headquarters believe it or
not the only thing that gives it away is
that there's no sheep here but we spend
ages recreating this block for block
again mining it all out so that it looks
like the real deal and then obviously
what's happened is that they have fallen
for it have they taken a chair because
here it is the fake Vault the fake
diamond Throne Vault it has exploded so
I feel confident that I can show this to
you on camera because it seems that
someone on hip has infiltrated in
quotation marks the mycelium
headquarters they've Fallen yet again
for another mind games of the devious
green and impulse and they have suffered
the consequences they've blown up this
is the fake headquarters and you don't
even know how many fake headquarters
we've got hmm how many have we got the
plan worked yet again
man I love this thing I love the Mycelia
resistance storyline this is going
amazingly and I don't I don't actually
have much more to say to it that they've
yet again fallen for our Antics the only
downside to this of course is that I'm
actually unable to show you before they
fall for the Mind Games I have to always
wait until they've fallen for it before
I can actually show it on camera man I
really want to do trick-or-treating
again oh B-Dubs he's getting in the
Mumbo self-portrait spookificator oh
hello there the face buddy I wanna see
honestly I'm gonna wait here well there
he goes
we just get to watch this I guess
eventually he explodes right Kaboom
kaboom how is he still alive
[Laughter]
what's going on looks like looks like
I'm gonna have to do this the
old-fashioned way here we go bye bye
B-Dubs he looks exactly the same it it
hasn't worked oh
oh
that's so cursed I see I see I see what
I see what you did then oh no I don't
like this I know like I I don't like
this
I'll beat up just played the Uno reverse
card wait
am I hip now
oh those eyes they're beautiful
and scary we must we literally we have
to fix this stop stop getting up in my
grill
stop it okay okay okay okay
if we run at each other
real fast will it swap right ready
three
two one
run
okay right that should do it
that should do it
boom there we go hey and B-Dubs is back
as well
our faces uh back to normal we did the
old switcheroo
the old Switcheroo never
fails
beautiful you beautiful man if only he
knew that I keep a beat Up's head on me
at all times
or are you in the resistance
hmm
perfect absolutely perfect our face is
back to normal just in time for the end
of Halloween however if there is still
something we need to do for Halloween on
the hermitcraft server we like to make
games for each other for example decked
out what on Earth is this sorry again
I've been distracted
wow
jeez
the hip don't mess around I thought that
was their base what's this now mumbo's
just got like a podzel thing going on
what is going on here
I'm so confused all the time now
I can't keep up I don't know how you
guys keep up if I can't okay right so it
looks like the Hep have a huge Factory
and a big llama base
okay it doesn't look finished on the
inside and gentleman's rules dictate
that we let them finish what they do
before we go and have a look a closer
look so I mean we admire from afar we're
aware of it we're definitely gonna have
to infiltrate this and see what's going
on but like I said gentlemen's rules on
the hermitcraft server dictate we let
them finish because this is quite the
project I mean can we just appreciate
for a second how talented I assume Mrs
scar this has got scar written all over
it how talented scar is at building this
has just appeared overnight and there's
now a Turf shop as well I'm loving this
I think this area of the shopping
district is my favorite by far
so ignoring that for a second I actually
have an idea to help us with this whole
mycelium grass
War thing man the shopping District's
busy so what I was thinking is if we
take down the hermit land jobs board
board isn't that's not the correct board
I guess it's what you do if you're bored
so if I take this down and I turn this
into the turf war communication board
this way we can leave messages to each
other and make sure that everything
stays Fair because actually we've still
seen some really nasty comments and
guess what in this storyline pretty much
anything goes if they want to blow up
the mycelium resistance HQ good luck to
them if we want to infiltrate the Hep
headquarters we will if you see it on
the hermitcraft server it's a-okay
there's no rules we do what we like so
we don't need to see any nasty comments
however I am going to leave a sign that
says if you if you sneak into the
mycelium resistance HQ you will lose
items so you can't say that we didn't
warn them we will defend and our base oh
my goodness
okay okay
then no no
false no no bad cursed that actually
spooked me a little bit and then of
course we can add other signs just to
banter with each other is like is the
Hep base a cool futuristic Tower or a
llama I don't know so I've kind of
started off this whole thing and
hopefully we can get some good
communication going between the two
sides and kind of mess with each other a
little bit so I've given them fair
warning we will defend our base and I
assume they will defend theirs as well
so if you take your items to the HQ like
if you're wearing your armor and you die
and you lose your items it's now no
longer our fault and also if we lose our
items because we forgot to take them off
if we ever Infiltrate The Hep
headquarters
then that's on us as well but anyway
ignoring all that there is another mini
game on the hermitcraft server that I
want to check out just before Halloween
ends and the instructions were to go
through this tunnel
there we go Haunted Mansion this way
so this was built by stress monster and
I really don't know what to expect going
in WoW
wow that's a pretty decent looking build
okay I'm excited to play this mini game
okay there's a big wall of instructions
okay this looks super complicated let's
put all our stuff away so I'm gonna read
this and give you the too long didn't
read okay so I can choose a class
basically it's a collect-a-thon I need
to go into the Mansion collect loads of
stuff
and yeah basically that's kind of it
four pumpkin pies are allowed per run
because Halloween excellent so Archer
won by 10 arrows Warrior Stone ax tank
one stone home one leather pants I think
I'm gonna take the stone ax okay so I
don't know whether it starts literally
now or maybe the entrance is over here I
don't know where the start of this is I
think it perhaps starts immediately okay
right it starts immediately so I don't
think there's any timed runs or anything
so
as far as I'm aware I think I can just
go for it and try and find barrels
what's behind the iron door how do I
activate the iron door flush the toilet
maybe there's a lot of buttons
that are just for decoration it seems
and I haven't actually figured out how
to open anything
can I go walking around the outside I
assume I can
whoa okay right
that was uh that was almost extremely
dangerous I
almost fell into my death no problem
nope that that's lava
but there is there is a hidden Trinket
in there my goodness I need to stop
jumping through these paintings so
haphazardly use what you've got and
don't fall
hmm
is that for pumpkin pies
and don't fall okay we got it
got the trinket
whoa
okay think carefully
foreign
there we go easy peasy I'll be honest
with you I didn't think carefully at all
I just pressed that button
see this button I can hear this button
doing something maybe this is one for
the Archer where you've got to put an
arrow in it and then it holds but I'm
not the Archer
in fact the stone ax hasn't really been
needed at all okay
oh we got a cookie
oh no no
that's not fair part of me wants to run
it again but the other part of me
I don't think I could do it
I spent like half an hour in this
Mansion I got a load of Trinkets and
then I died
okay I can't let I can't go out on that
so what I'm gonna do is basically like
speed run it and this time I'm gonna try
the Archer right so this time I'm gonna
start downstairs and work systematically
I knew it
if back is front and left is right who
decides ah there we go oh my goodness
that was uh that was a risky play
I didn't actually think about the riddle
at all okay that was what killed me last
time I'm up to I'm up to how many five
trinkets so I'm almost back where I was
now what did this do
right that opens something over there
again with the death
that's not cool
oh
man okay so you definitely want to be
archer in this game
nice I don't know I don't actually know
how I open this we're doing way better
this time round I'm thinking of I'm now
that I've got quite a substantial amount
of trinkets I'm thinking of Calling it
Quits I have no idea how many trinkets
there are but I actually have a lot and
I've almost died a lot so I'm thinking
of calling it it's so easy to get lost
here that I don't actually know where
I've been and where I haven't
okay deep dark scary dungeon
I'm gonna be annoyed if I die because
I've got a huge amount of trinkets now
I'm getting really nervous now
okay
yeah this is quite spooky you know this
isn't spooky at all okay I'm getting out
of here I've had enough and last trinket
okay I'm calling it so I did a pretty
quick Speed Run of that and this is how
many I got so I'm guessing there's a lot
more trinkets than this but I'm pretty
happy with this so I'll take this grave
grin and then we put in oh of our train
kits well I think we've done reasonably
well and that is officially the end
because it says once you've put your
trinkets into the grave you are finished
with the Mansion no more runs
so I think we did pretty well there I'm
not entirely sure how many trinkets
there are but there must be a fair few
but can we take a second to appreciate
how many hours must have gone into this
there's so many layers there's like
several flaws to this I may have even
missed an entire floor it goes all the
way to bedrock there's so much Redstone
in here GG stress what a game so I hope
I've done pretty well on that there's
been some very fun Halloween games today
very very fun Halloween games
so I'm afraid that is probably all we
have time for today we've actually done
quite a lot even though some of it was
mainly mini games and stuff but you've
got to enjoy what the other Hermits have
created so thank you very much for
watching and I shall see you in the next
episode where hopefully
we can try and do something against
whatever is going on over here this is
the most interesting development of this
episode
and we've got to wait and see what
happens with it but we've got plans of
our own at the resistance and we'll get
into that in the next episode good bye